Guide to the Southern Pacific Company Drawings and Maps
Department of Special Collections
Southern Pacific Company drawings and maps
ca. 1870-1965
MSS PRINTS 0007
Southern Pacific Company.
78 maps
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection includes 78 maps produced by Southern Pacific Railroad of lines, sidings, stations, and rail yards in California, primarily in the San Francisco Bay Area but also including the Santa Barbara region.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2000.
Scope and Content of Collection
Contains 78 maps produced by Southern Pacific Railroad of lines, sidings, stations, and rail yards in California, primarily in the San Francisco Bay Area but also including the Santa Barbara region.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Railroads--California--History.; Transportation.
Related Material
Baldwin-Lima-Hamilton Corp. Records, M0015
Southern Pacific Railroad Records, M1010
Collection Contents
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division Station plan of San Jose: study of train yard ground air facilities, 1958 Aug. 8, rev. 1958 Aug. 22.1958 Aug., Drawing no. 42132; 1 map; 89 x 254 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division station plan of San Francisco Islais Creek, San Francisco County: proposed WP connection1961 Apr. 24, Drawing no. 42155; 1 map; 89 x 183 cm. Note: damaged and needs repairs, right side (Box 1, Folder 2)
- San Francisco to Santa Barbara, M.P 243 to M.P. 291, Roll 5n.d., Roll 5; 1 map; 89 x 242 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Decoto proposed future industrial development of the Zwissig Estate: amended plan of Decoto, Alameda County, Calif., filed Dec. 1, 1904, 1955 Feb. 17, rev. 1956 Sept. 6, Drawing no. D-590; 1 map; 81 x 159 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Southern Pacific Co. Office of Division Engineer, Decoto, proposed industrial development of Southern Pacific property, 1962 Aug. 29 - 1964 Sept. 11, Drawing no. D-590; 1 map; 81 x 168 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, South San Francisco, Cabot & Forbes Industrial Park, 1964 Mar. 31, Drawing no. 42165; 1 map; 91 x 170 cm. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Branches, San Jose to Santa Cruz, Mountain View to U.S. Navy Air base, n.d., 1 map; 91 x 238 cm. Note: damage on right edge (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Southern Pacific Co. South San Francisco, proposed industrial development, 1946 Nov. 13; rev. 1947 Jan. 8, Drawing no. 42092; 1 map; 91 x 167 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Line, Decoto, proposed industrial development of Zwissig Estate, 1955 Feb. 17, Drawing no.; 1 map; 81 x 161 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Map of the City of Santa Cruz, California, Sheet 1 of 11952 Feb. 5, Drawing no. 2059; 1 map: negative image; 90 x 116 cm. Note: badly damaged (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Southern Pacific Company Pacific Lines San Francisco. Proposed Rearrangement of Yard Tracks at 16th Street Between 3rd and 7th Streets.1961 July 19, Drawing no. 42158; 1 map; 91 x 151 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Southern Pacific Company Pacific Lines. Santa Clara. Proposed Industrial Development.1945 Sept. 18, Drawing no. 2088; 1 map: negative image; 76 x 143 cm. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Southern Pacific Company. Office of Division Engineer. Dumbarton.1963 July 26, Drawing no. D-829; 1 map; 94 x 133 cm. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Southern Pacific Company Pacific Lines. Simla. Proposed Relocation Portion of Permanente Spur.1959 Oct. 22, Drawing no. 42141; 1 map; 79 x 135 cm. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- South San Francisco Industrial Park. Owner and Developer Utah Construction and Mining Company.n.d., Drawing no. 42142; 1 map; 77 x 115 cm. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Southern Pacific Company Pacific Lines. Belmont Industrial Development.1945 Nov. 27, Drawing no. 42090; 1 map; 81 x 91 cm. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- San Augustine derailment of 110NY June 19, Drawing no. 42042; 1 map; 95 x 104 cm. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Southern Pacific Company Pacific Lines. San Jose. Possible relocation of interchange tracks. 1950 Aug. 15; rev. 1952 June 13, Drawing no. 42096; 1 map; 78 x 87 cm. Damaged and repaired left side (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Southern Pacific Company. San Francisco. Existing and proposed trackage.1944 Sept. 20, rev. 1944 Oct. 9, Drawing no. 42086; 1 map; 92 x 132 cm. Note: torn on right side. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Proposed San Lorenzo - Scotts Valley zone. Santa Cruz County Flood Control and Water Conservation District.1957 Aug., Drawing no. 42120; 1 map; 97 x 90 cm. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division station plan of Bayshore - Visitacion capacity of train yard, 1962 May 21, Drawing no. 42161; 1 map; 90 x 266 cm. (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, Sunnyvale: propsed trackage to serve General Motors Corp., 1956 Dec. 5, Drawing no. 42114; 1 map; 94 x 116 cm. (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Southern Pacific Co. classification yard, West Oakland, 1944 Mar. 13, Drawing no. O-2131; 1 map; 86 x 275 cm. Note: water damaged on right side (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines: proposed facilities for Kirkham Street freight station, Oakland, Calif., 1944 Aug. 3, Drawing no. O-2181; 1 map; 83 x 149 cm. (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division station plan of Bayshore - Visitacion, San Francisco & San Mateo Counties: train yard ground air facilities at Bayshore, 1958 Aug. 8: rev. 1958 Aug. 18, Drawing no. 42133; 1 map; 92 x 187 cm. (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, Oakland: proposed Bancroft Ave. Highway. Sheet no. 1, 1942 Mar. 18; rev. 1954 May 25, Drawing no. O-1983; 1 map; 72 x 379 cm. (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Southern Pacific Co. San Francisco, Mission Bay Area - Townsend to 16th Streets, 1958 Jan. 3, Drawing no. 42126; 1 map; 93 x 150 cm. (Box 6, Folder 27)
- [Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division Islais Creek, San Francisco County][196?], Drawing no. 42094; 1 map; 92 x 168 cm. Note: damaged on right side, legend is missing (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Southern Pacific Co. San Francisco (Mission Bay) location of oil and water lines, 1932 Feb. 16, Drawing no. 42066; 1 map; 89 x 134 cm. (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division, station plan of San Francisco, Mission Bay & Jackson Square capacity of train yard, 1962 May 21, Drawing no. 42161; 1 map; 92 x 183 cm. (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division, station plan of San Francisco, Mission Bay & Jackson Square: tentative car storage tracks, 1931 Jan. - 1942 Feb. 18, Drawing no. 42081; 1 map; 90 x 180 cm. (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, San Francisco Mission Bay yards: proposed and existing trackage, 6 & 16th Streets, 1944 Oct. 4, Drawing no. 42086; 1 map; 92 x 138 cm. (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, San Francisco Mission Bay yards: proposed and existing trackage, 6 & 16th Streets, 1944 Sept. 20, Drawing no. 42086; 1 map; 92 x 132 cm. (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines San Luis Obispo, Port San Luis Harbor District1953 Dec. 30, Drawing no. 42105; 1 map; 93 x 123 cm. (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Redwood City proposed interconnection to Redwood Harbor spur, 1952 Aug. 28; rev. 1952 Oct. 6, 1953 Apr. 6, Drawing no. 42101; 1 map; 92 x 224 cm. (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines San Luis Obispo right-of-way and contour lines with proposed yards and square engine house, 1920 Oct. 20, Drawing no. 42048; 1 map; 94 x 216 cm. (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Melrose to Elmhurst proposed trackage, Oakland Pier, 1945 Apr. 25, Drawing no. M-765; 1 map; 227 x 108 cm. (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Oakland proposed tail track relocation / prepared in Office of Divn. Eng. Oak. Pier, 1948 Mar. 31, Drawing no. O-2533; 1 map; 75 x 285 cm. (Box 8, Folder 38)
- San Francisco terminal yard plan, 3rd to 9th Street, 1915 Nov., 1 map; 104 x 336 cm. (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines station plan of San Francisco, 2nd to 11th Street: proposed Southern freeway, 1960 June 15; rev. 1960 Dec. 2, Drawing no. 42148; 1 map; 92 x 182 cm. (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines San Francisco proposed southern freeway, Station plan San Francisco - Islais Creek, 1957 Jan. 17, Drawing no. 42118; 1 map; 92 x 182 cm. (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Millbrae - Burlingame proposed industrial development of Millbrae industrial park, 1955 Mar. 1, Drawing no. 45106; 1 map; 76 x 172 cm. Negative image (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines station plan of Isl[ais Creek], San F[rancisco], n.d., 1 map; 92 x 154 cm. Needs conservation treatment (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Southern Pacific Co. Paso Robles proposed line change / prepared in Office of Division Engineer, San Francisco, California, 1935 Oct., Drawing no. 42068; 1 map; 92 x 304 cm. (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Coast Division station plan of South San Francisco: capacity of train yard, n.d., Drawing no. 42161; 1 map; 62 x 212 cm. (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Benicia U.S. Govt. Station plan,1948, Drawing no. B-1205, sheet no. 1; 1 map; 68 x 134 cm. (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Benicia U.S. Govt. Station plan,1948, Drawing no. B-1205, sheet no. 2; 1 map; 68 x 134 cm. (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Benicia U.S. Govt. Station plan,1948, Drawing no. B-1205, sheet no. 3; 1 map; 68 x 134 cm. (Box 10, Folder 48)
- Benicia U.S. Govt. Station plan,1948, Drawing no. B-1205, sheet no. 4; 1 map; 68 x 134 cm. (Box 10, Folder 49)
- Benicia U.S. Govt. Station plan,1948, Drawing no. B-1205, sheet no. 5; 1 map; 68 x 134 cm. (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division station plan of Watsonville Jct., Monterey County / prepared in Office of Division Engineer, San Francisco, Calif., 1947 Oct.; rev. 1949 Oct. 1, 1 map; 62 x 312 cm. (Box 11, Folder 51)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, Suisun-Fairfield proposed 100-car siding / prepared in Office of Division Engineer, Oakland Pier, Calif., 1929 Feb., Drawing no. S-570; 1 map; 62 x 146 cm. (Box 11, Folder 52)
- Southern Pacific Co. Elmhurst abandoned Stonehurst branch, 1921 Mar., Drawing no. E-30; 1 map; 63 x 140 cm. (Box 11, Folder 53)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines, Oakland Pier, 1963 Jan. 29, Drawing no. O-4387; 1 map; 62 x 224 cm. (Box 11, Folder 54)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pittsburgh proposed relocation of A.T. Division and S.F.Ry. & S.P.Co. interchange / prepared in Office of Division Engineer, Oakland Pier, 1928 Oct., Drawing no. P-216; 1 map; 62 x 143 cm. (Box 11, Folder 55)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Davis highway changes1960 May 13, Drawing no. D-739; 1 map; 23 x 177 cm. (Box 12, Folder 56)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Davis repairs to station platform, 1944 Nov. 16, Drawing no. D-328; 1 map; 36 x 122 cm. (Box 12, Folder 57)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Davis proposed road crossing, 1965 Jan. 8, Drawing no. D-856; 1 map; 61 x 101 cm. (Box 12, Folder 58)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Davis retired trackage, 1953 July 27; rev. 1953 Aug. 19; 1953 Dec. 22; 1954 Feb. 11, Drawing no. D-555; 1 map; 63 x 186 cm. (Box 12, Folder 59)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Emeryville proposed crossing, 1952 Jan. 4, Drawing no. E-967; 1 map; 44 x 121 cm. (Box 12, Folder 60)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Mountain View proposed retirement of center siding, 1960 Feb. 9, Drawing no. 42143; 1 map; 62 x 176 cm. (Box 13, Folder 61)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines East Oakland / prepared in the Office of Division Engineer, Oakland, 1942 May 21, Drawing no. E-526; 1 map; 51 x 114 cm. (Box 13, Folder 62)
- Southern Pacific Co. Coast Division station plan of Redwood City capacity train yard, 1962 May 21, Drawing no. 42161; 1 map; 62 x 142 cm. (Box 13, Folder 63)
- San Francisco Oakland and San Jose Ry, 22nd Street Junction, Yerba Buena yard, Oakland, California, 1906 Jan. 23, Drawing no. E-10; 1 map; 46 x 133 cm. (Box 13, Folder 64)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Oakland, 16th Street hold yard, 1947 Oct. 20; rev. 1947 Nov. 17, Drawing no. O-2493; 1 map; 46 x 195 cm. (Box 13, Folder 65)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Oleum proposed track changes Union Oil Co., 1954 Dec. 1; rev. 1955 June 14, Drawing no. O-3048; 1 map; 62 x 160 cm. original item (Box 14, Folder 66)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Oleum proposed track changes Union Oil Co., 1954 Dec. 1; rev. 1955 June 14, Drawing no. O-3048; 1 map; 62 x 160 cm. transparency duplicate (Box 14, Folder 67)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Oakland rearrange trackage along Bancroft Ave., step 3, 1957 Sept. 12, Drawing no. O-3058; 1 map; 61 x 233 cm. (Box 14, Folder 68)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines San Lucas proposed siding extension to hold 100 cars, 1941 July 18; rev. 1941 Oct. 2, Drawing no. 42080; 1 map; 61 x 181 cm. (Box 14, Folder 69)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Emeryville proposed realignment of spur track, 1950 July 30, Drawing no. E-900; 1 map; 33 x 145 cm. (Box 14, Folder 70)
- San Pablo to Giant cross sections of proposed yard, 1941 Aug. 14, Drawing no. S-1043; 1 map; 56 x 254 cm. (Box 15, Folder 71)
- Richmond to Oakland possible industrial .... n.d., Drawing no. R-945; 1 map; 43 x 126 cm. Note: map represents one-half of larger document; whereabouts of remaining half unknown. (Box 15, Folder 72)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Melrose to Elmhurst proposed siding extension / prepared in Office of Division Engineer, Oakland Pier, 1936 Sept.; rev. 1937 Apr. 19, Drawing no. M-388, sheet 1; 1 map; 37 x 215 cm. (Box 15, Folder 73)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Melrose to Elmhurst proposed siding extension / prepared in Office of Division Engineer, Oakland Pier, 1936 Sept.; rev. 1940 Nov. 26, Drawing no. M-388, sheet 3; 1 map; 37 x 215 cm. (Box 15, Folder 74)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines Emeryville improve Doyle Street, 1950 Feb. 20; rev. 1952 Apr. 10, Drawing no. E-872; 1 map; 32 x 124 cm. (Box 15, Folder 75)
- San Francisco possible industrial development east of 3rd street, 1954 Nov. 24; 1955 Dec. 7, Drawing no. 42094; 1 map; 61 x 92 cm. (Box 16, Folder 76)
- King City, n.d., Drawing no. 328; 1 map; 64 x 122 cm. + 1 aerial photograph (Box 16, Folder 77)
- Southern Pacific Co. Pacific Lines East Oakland proposed trackage Bay Area Rapid Transit District showing encroachment S.P.Co. land and facilities, 1964 Feb. 6, Drawing no. E-1523; 1 map; 45 x 123 cm. (Box 16, Folder 78)